Guide to the Cornell University Lacrosse Films and Ephemera Collection,1962-1980.
Cornell University Lacrosse Films and Ephemera Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Lacrosse Films and Ephemera Collection, 1962-1980.
40-5-3096
Cornell University.
43 reels, 21 videos, 17 slides.
Films, videos, and slides.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Movie video, slides and ephemera of Cornell University lacrosse games.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Films, videos, and slides of Cornell University lacrosse games. Also audio tape with a sound bite from Richie Moran. Booklet from the 1976 season filled with clippings about the season's games, Cornell Lacrosse Club Annual Awards Banquet programs.
Digitization of films can be arranged if requested.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University--Athletics.
Subjects:
Lacrosse--New York (State)
Form and Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Videotapes.; Slides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Listed chronologically by date and by opponent's name, when known.
Some films labeled highlights may refer to a single game.
CONTAINER LIST
- Videos
  - 16 mm film: Dartmouth #1, 1962 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Dartmouth #2, 1962 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Dartmouth #3, 1962 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Dartmouth #4, 1962 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: So Trip, 1962 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Baltimore, 1965 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Baltimore #1, 1965 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Baltimore #2, 1965 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Maryland, 1965 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Penn, 5/1/65, 1965 (Box 1)
    Available on DVD #139
  - 16 mm film: Princeton, 5/22/65, 1965 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Navy, 1965 (Box 2)
    Available on DVD #136, 11:00
  - 16 mm film: Cornell 13-Princeton 9, Ivy League, 1969 (Box 1)
  - 8 mm film: Brown (reels 4-6, 7 missing), 1971; 4-6 (Box 3)
  - 8 mm film: unidentified (3 reels) Early frames are identified by a road sign that says North Carolina State University, but Cornell didn't play N.C. State in 1971, 8-10 (Box 3)
  - 8 mm film: Penn (reels 11[1]-12[2]), 1971; 11-12 (Box 3)
    Available on DVD #140 part 1 and #141 part 2 Part of this game was played during a snow storm. At one point a dog enters the field of play. Richie Moran can be seen in part 2.
  - 8 mm film: Princeton (reels 13[1]-16[IV], 1971; 13-16 (Box 3)
  - 8 mm film: Christmas Party, 1971;Harvard at Cornell, 1st Quarter, 1971-1972; 21 (Box 3)
  - 8 mm film: Harvard at Cornell, 2nd, 3rd, 4th Quarters, 1972; 20 (Box 3)
  - 8 mm film: illegible (#1) Looks like a first and second half of a game played at alumni field at Cornell. Opposing team has dark shorts and white tops and helmets., 1972 (?); 22-23 (Box 3)
  - 17 Slides: Penn [written over label Brown away, Army game], 1972 (Box 3)
  - 8 mm film: unidentified (7 reels) in envelopes. Appear to all be from the same game at Schoellkopf stadium., 1972; 1-3, 5-8 (Box 3)
  - 16 mm film: Taped on label says U. Mass, 10/27/1973 Fall exhibition game, 12-8. [label is taped over can which says Cornell vs. Brown reels 3-6 (Box 1)
  - 1/2" Video: Hopkins (III), 1975 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Hopkins (IV), 1975 (Box 2)
  - 8 mm film: Cornell vs. Maryland #1, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 8 mm film: Cornell vs. Maryland #2, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 16 mm film: Lacrosse highlights, Maryland vs. Cornell, NCAA Championship at Brown University, May 29, 1976 (Box 1)
    Color and narration. Available on DVD #137, 16:00. Cornell wins 16-13 in O.T. features Mike French and Eamon McEneaney of Cornell and Frank Urso of Maryland.
  - 1/2" Video: Hopkins I, NCAA Semifinal, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Hopkins II, NCAA Semifinal, 1976 (Box 2)
  - 16 mm film: NCAA Lacrosse: Quarter-final Cornell-U Mass; Semi-final Cornell-Navy, large, 1977 (Box 1)
  - 8 mm film: Cornell vs. Hopkins: 1st Half, 1977 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Hobart (Per I-II), 1978 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Hobart (Per III-IV), 1978 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: U Mass (Per III), 1978 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: U Mass (Per IV), 1978 (Box 2)
  - 16 mm film: Cornell-Hobart lacrosse (Part II), 1978 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Cornell-Yale lacrosse, large, 1978 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: North South lacrosse (original negative, do not project), 1978 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Cornell-Hopkins, 4-14-79 (Reel #2), 1979 (Box 1)
    Available on DVD #138, 11:00, end shows Hopkins scoring on a lob from half field.
  - 1/2" Video: Cortland Game (2 reels), 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Hobart 1-2, 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Hobart 3-4, 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Syracuse (2 reels), 1980 (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: C.S.C. 140 Kutztown 83 (Check with Bob Jullian), 1983 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Lacross[e], #2 Mt. Wash (Mount Washington), n.d. (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: Cornell-Maryland Reel #3 (Box 1)
  - 16 mm film: National Varsity Club, Skillbuilder Film 4, La crosse, large, n.d. (Box 1)
  - 1/2" Video: Cornell-Navy Per 1-2, Semifinals, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Cornell-Navy Per 3-4, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Cornell-Navy R1, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: Cornell-Navy R2, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 1/2" Video: 1, n.d. (Box 2)
- Audio, CD-1840*
  Audio cassette has been digitized and is available on CD. *Note this CD is in box 3 of collection 40-4-3590. The recording is not complete nor professional, recorded by Fleet Morse.
  - 1986 25th Annual Hockey Awards Banquet, tape ends with lacrosse clip., April 12, 1986; TR-9361 (Box 3*)
    This tape is located in the Cornell Hockey collection, #40-4-3590, not in this collection. Recorded at The Party House 417 W. State Street. Includes: Side A Lou Reycroft Season recap and player introductions, presentation of year end awards. Other speakers include moderator Bud Hall, Doug Dadswell, Joe Nieuwendyk, Mark Canduro, Dr. Dan Yale. Side B Presentation of awards, speakers include Fleet Morse, Dave Hunter, Dale Coats, Duane Moeser, Wendell Earle, Peter Natyshak, George Taber, Donald Fawcett, Helen Cooley, Laing Kennedy, Doug Dadswell, Mike Schafer Also Cornell lacrosse news coverage including Roy Simmons Jr. and Richie Moran, Syracuse lacrosse postgame coverage versus Syracuse from April 12, 1986. Lastly radio coverage of the hockey award.
  - Season recap show, May 20, 2002; TR-9366 (Box 3)
    Includes Barry Leonard, Jeff Tambroni, Bobby Wynne, Jenny Grapp
- Ephemera
  - Cornell Lacrosse Club Annual Banquet and Awards Programs, 1975, 1981,1982, 1983, 1985 (Box Mss. 38)
  - 1976 Cornell Lacrosse news clippings booklet, 1976 (Box Mss. 38)
  - 1977 Cornell Lacrosse season booklet, 1977 (Box Mss. 38)
- "It's Great to be Here"